One man lives in the neighborhood, another man owns it. A devoted father
battles the local crime boss for the life of his son.
A Bronx Tale is a drama, crime film directed by Robert De Niro.
Set in the Bronx during the tumultuous 1960s, an adolescent boy is torn between his
honest, working-class father and a violent yet charismatic crime boss.
Complicating matters is the youngster's growing attraction -
forbidden in his neighborhood - for a beautiful black girl.
Lorenzo Anello, played by Robert De Niro.
Sonny LoSpecchio, played by Chazz Palminteri.
Calogero 'C' Anello (Age 17), played by Lillo Brancato.
Calogero 'C' Anello (Age 9), played by Francis Capra.
Jane Williams, played by Taral Hicks.
Rosina Anello, played by Kathrine Narducci.
A Bronx Tale is a 1993 American coming-of-age crime drama film directed by and starring Robert De Niro in his
directorial debut and produced by Jane Rosenthal, adapted from Chazz Palminteri's 1989 one-man play.
It tells the coming-of-age story of an Italian-American boy, Calogero, who, after encountering a local Mafia boss, is torn between the
temptations of organized crime and the values of his honest, hardworking father, as well as racial tensions in his community.
The Broadway production was converted to film with limited changes.
De Niro, who first viewed the play in Los Angeles in 1990, acquired the rights from
Palminteri, with the intent of making the play his directorial debut.
The duo worked heavily together on the screenplay, with Palminteri aiming to retain many of the
aspects of the original script, as it was based largely on his own childhood.
Production began in 1991, and was funded in collaboration with De Niro's Tribeca
Productions and Savoy Pictures, as the first film released by each studio.
A Bronx Tale premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 14,
1993, and was released in the United States on September 29, 1993.
The film achieved limited commercial success, grossing
more than $17 million domestically.
However, it fared much better with critics, who praised the performances of the leads, and launched
Palminteri's acting career, while also helping De Niro gain acceptance as a director.
The film explores themes of italian american, gambling,
funeral, italian, parent child relationship.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.